Hello!
Yes... I know...
it's been a long time we haven't seen each others...
therefore, to show how repentant I am,
it is not one tutorial I am offering you today,
but two!!
Indeed, I wanted to teach you
how to make a unicorn.
However, if we think about it,
a unicorn looks a lot like a horse...
with a horn!
I will therefore teach you how to make
a horse and how to make a unicorn!!
Are you ready? Let's go!!
I took a brown balloon, so we can see it better.
To make the horse, it is important not to blow the balloon too much.
The knot must be done at the very tip of the balloon.
Look, how much extra balloon space we got that way.
So, please review the tutorial about air pressure.
Let's start with an eccentric (off-centered ? or offset?) bubble,
where the knot will be placed on the side of the bubble,
as was done with the giraffe.
Two ears...
not too big...
and not with too much pressure.
Then...
the neck...
it is a horse, not a giraffe,
so, a neck much smaller!
There it is... like this,
and just like before, an 'offset' bubble
Now we will make the mane.
So...
we shall make four very small bubbles.
There... four small bubbles...
all exactly with the same size,
which we will tuck behind the ears.
And now we will make,
four other bubbles exactly with the same size,
in parallel.
Now...
we will pinch the base of the two last bubbles
and also pinch
the middle of the series of bubbles,
this way, and we will rotate,
very simply this way,
the four bubbles at the base will be rotated against the others,
to lock all the bubbles together.
There it is, we now have...
the horse head.
We will now thin this part of the balloon,
but we will try not to push the air all the way to the end,
because at this moment, we still need to preserve...
preserve this margin of non inflated balloon here.
We make a mental note where the half of the balloon,
and then the quarter (half of half),
and that will help us gauge how to size
and make the first front leg,
followed by the second front leg,
with exactly the same size.
Good!!
Now the body,
then one back leg, same size as the two front legs,
and we do not want to end with a very long tail,
and actually, this size is pretty good.
Now we will give the tail a proper shape.
Hold the tail in the middle, with a smaller bubble on the end part,
I pinch firmly on that small bubble,
and I release slowly...
until I get the desired shape I was looking for.
Well and good! This is my little horse.
All that is left to do is a little drawing.
And here is the little horse!!
And now, the unicorn!
We will need two balloons,
I chose a white balloon
for the body and head of the unicorn,
and pink, of course, for the mane, the tail and the horn.
We shall start by inflating the pink balloon,
but, not much,
there, that will be for the tail
I tie a knot and put it aside for the moment,
I will need it soon.
I know inflate the white balloon.
but this time, I do not have to worry too much about the air pressure management,
which means that I'm inflating it
with much less margin than I did for the horse
although I do need some nonetheless.
We will start, as we did for the horse,
by making a small eccentric (offset) bubble
with a fold on the side,
followed by the two ears,
not too compressed either.
There you go.
Here, a small variation,
we will make a small bubble,
which we will turn into a pinch-twist,
like this.
For the neck, a bubble a bit longer than the head,
at least,
which we will angle, so that we can fold eccentrically (on the side),
like this.
A front leg, a little longer than....
Hmm.. wait, I'll push the air forward a bit.
A front leg...
a little longer than the neck,
another front leg which we lock together with the first one as usual,
a tummy, but not very long,
and here,
for the back legs,
we compare with the front legs to ensure we have the same size,
but before locking the second leg together with the first one,
we hold them this way,
and...
we get the pink balloon back,
which we will tie to the excess of white bubble
that we pierce to deflate
and, we tie them together.
I cut the small bits to ensure they won't get in the way,
and now, and only now,
will I lock the two back legs together.
And now,
we will make a small bubble at the base of the tail,
which we will turn into a pinch-twist.
The tail must go down
with a curve that go this way
and then, that way.
So, we pinch it, and let it come back...
See, here it goes down, which is good,
and now, we make it go back up...
Maybe we'll do the knot first.
We cut the excess balloon that we keep preciously,
since we will need
for the mane and for the horn.
And now...
Another pinching here,
There it is!
It is exactly what I wanted.
We take back what is left of the pink balloon,
which must be inflated a little less than the neck.
Tie the knot,
like that,
and you will then lock this knot with the pinch-twist.
We will now make a series of small bubbles
as we did for the horse.
one,
two,
three,
but this time, instead of making only four bubbles,
we will make five, since this neck is quite big,
four,
and five!
we lock them at the fold between the neck and the front legs.
And then we will come back the other way, with five new bubbles.
one,
two,
three,
four,
and at this point,
the fifth bubble must be a bit larger than the fourth one
because, we will try to have...
a small bulge at the base of the horn.
I lock the horn with its small bulge
with the pinch twist,
and now,
there is a set of 4 bubbles at the base (of the ears)
another 4 at the middle, and 2 at the base of the neck,
we shall then make the set of 4 bubbles in the middle rotate on itself
There it is!
The only thing left to do now is a little drawing.
Here is our lovely little balloon unicorn
It definitely involves more work than with the horse.
It is a very popular model and is very appreciated.
Well, that is all for today,
but let me remind you that all my videos
come with a step-by-step photo guide
which revisits every detail of the tutorials in a very clear manner.
You will find a link in the description of the video
or else, in the little info box that appeared , right there
under my finger
Well, that's it for me,
See you soon, for another lesson, with Môssieur Ballon!